This video is sponsored by boot.dev.
There are over 27,000
Magic the Gathering cards, and with what
feels like new cards getting added to
the game every other month, it's getting
harder and harder to find what you're
looking for, especially if you're
looking for a hidden gem for your
commander deck. So, in this video, I
wanted to cover the most powerful Magic
the Gathering search tool, Scriall, plus
show you one of the most underutilized
features on the site, so you can find
what you need and what you didn't even
know you needed faster. For those that
don't know, Scri is effectively gatherer
on steroids. Not only that, it contains
links to downloadable highquality card
images which you see in every video on
this channel. It also has relevant links
to EDHR wreck, other deck building
tools, and pricing. But perhaps my
favorite thing on this whole site is the
search bar. And this is what sets it
apart from every other site. Now, before
I get into this, I know there are some
people who are going to say you can use
the advanced search function. And yes,
you totally can. But the search bar is
one of those features like the command
line interface for my programming
viewers that once you start using it and
understanding how fast and specific you
can be, you won't want to stop using it.
The very basic functionality of the
search bar is it simply searches card
names. For example, if you typed forest
and hit enter, Scrile would return every
card that had the word forest in its
name, including if the word could be
found inside another word. For example,
the forest in Misty Rainforest.
Scrile also has a suggestion feature if
you're a terrible speller like me.
Scrile will ask you if you meant a
certain card based off your misspelling.
Now, let's talk about how to unlock the
secret powers of Scryfall. Scrile
syntax. Syntax is basically code that
the search engine understands.
Now, bear with me here as we're going to
start with the basics and work our way
up. Understanding the fundamentals is
crucial. Speaking of fundamentals, when
I'm not editing these videos, I work in
IT and I owe a lot of that to
self-studying coding. So, when the
sponsor of this video, Boot.dev, reached
out and I saw what they do, I honestly
wish I had something like this when I
was studying. Boot.dev is an online
learning platform that teaches you how
to code from start to finish. You can
learn Python, Go, JavaScript, and more.
When I first started out my coding
journey, I often found myself being
unsure of what to do next, or worse yet,
being stuck in tutorial hell. Boot.dev
removes all of that and gives you a
nice, clear path while helping you make
your own real life projects. How about
building your own version of asteroids
or a Pokédex? One of my favorite things
about boot.dev is Boots, the AI wizard
bear. It can help you out with any of
the curriculum questions as well as
answer any other questions about coding.
Or you can join the boot.dev discord to
chat to real people and get some help or
feedback on your work. Now you can sign
up to boot.dev for free and view all the
content as well as get a demo of the
interactive features. Then you can use
my code attack on cardboard to get 25%
off your first month or first year
subscription. links in the description
down below. Thanks again to boot.dev. To
start our scrile journey, we're going to
start with the keyword O for Oracle
text. If we head to the search bar and
type O colon open quote and then type a
specific phrase we're looking for, in
this case, counter target spell close
quote and hit enter, Scrile will search
every single card's oracle text for that
specific phrase.
To clarify, oracle text is the most
upto-date rules text for a card. The
original Rafa God says, "Bury all
creatures, but as you probably know, the
Oracle text says, "Destroy all
creatures. They can't be regenerated."
Editor: Attack on Cardboard here. Um,
actually, the fourth edition of Wrath of
God said, "Bury all creatures." The
original alpha printing of Wrath of God
said, "All creatures in play are
destroyed and cannot regenerate."
It's also important to note that the
Oracle search term doesn't search
through things like reminder text. So,
if we looked up the phrase, "You may
cast this spell for because perhaps
we're looking for cards with alternative
costs," it would only bring up the play
test card graveyard dig. But if we
instead search for full oracle text by
simply adding an F to our keyword, we
now get a bunch of cards with
alternative costs. So to recap, we use O
for oracle text and FO for full Oracle
text. Okay, now we're going to build on
this foundation. Let's say we're
building a Van Gold Waker Treasure
Commander deck and we want to see all of
the cards that make treasure tokens.
Well, we know that the spell or ability
is going to say the word treasure. So,
let's search that. O colon treasure.
Okay, so that brings up 346 results and
we can see some problems. First, we've
got alchemy cards that are no use to us.
We've also got green and blue cards that
we can't use. So, let's narrow down this
search. To do so, we can add some more
keywords to our search. Let's start with
F for format. Simply type F colon and
then the format of your choice. I
generally use C for commander. This will
remove all the alchemy and silverboarded
cards from the search results because
they're not legal in commander. Okay,
that brings us down from 346 to 314
cards. Let's keep going. The next
obvious step is to get rid of those
green and blue cards. So, there's two
keywords we can use here. The first is C
for color. So here you can either type
the names of the colors or simply use
the Wooberg abbreviations.
So if we wanted to search up Mardu
colors, we could either go C colon R W B
or we could go C colon MU. The color
keyword also accepts the common names of
colored groups.
Now we've got two problems here. First,
using just a colon here brings up cards
that contain the Mardu colors. So, that
would include five color cards, which is
what we don't want. And secondly, it
doesn't bring up any cards that are just
red, white, black, or any two color
combinations of them. Now, I could teach
you how to use the comparison
expressions here, but I personally think
that's a waste of time, especially when
we can just use a single keyword to
solve this whole problem. Let's check
out the keyword ID.
ID is short for color identity. And in
commander, you can obviously only
include the cards in your deck that
match your commander's color identity.
So, let's add this to our search.
And now we get cards that are colorless
or have red, white or black or any
combination of those colors. So this has
now dropped us down from 314 cards to
230.
And we can keep getting more specific.
What if we wanted to search for a
certain type of card? There's of course
a keyword for that. T for type. We can
type t colon artifact
and that will bring up 43 cars that have
the artifact type. The type keyword can
also search up subtypes, too. So, if we
wanted to look up vehicles, we could
just swap artifact for vehicle.
Or maybe we want to see what other
Marduk based treasure legends there are.
So, we can simply add legendary instead.
Okay, recap time. If we're searching for
a particular phrase or word on a card,
we can use O. And if we want to check
the reminder text, we use FO. Don't
forget your quotation marks. For format,
we use F. For color, we use C. But
remember, it will search explicitly for
those colors unless you use some
comparison expressions. So, usually I
like to use ID for color identity. Next,
we have T for type. Now, here's a couple
more that I regularly use. If I'm
searching for a particular keyword, I'll
use KW.
And if I happen to remember the set
abbreviation, I'll use the set keyword.
As I said, these seven keywords are what
I use on a regular basis when searching
through cards on Scriall.
These are the basics you should know.
And if at any point you need a
refresher, you can always click the
syntax button at the top of Scryfall to
see the full reference sheet. Okay, now
let's move on to the advanced stuff and
Scrifall's ultimate weapon. Let's say
you're looking for some removal for your
Van Gold Waker deck, but the only
removal spell you know about is
Doomblade and nothing else. Let's start
there on the Doom Blade page. Just below
the card in the toolbox section is our
secret weapon. Open on scrile tagger.
Let's click that. This will take us to
the tagger page for Doomlade.
Scrifle Tagger is a community project
that looks to categorize both what magic
cards do as well as the artwork found on
them. For example, if you wanted to
build a commander deck where everyone is
looking left in the artwork, there's a
tag for that. Or maybe you wanted to
build a trumpet deck. Well, there's a
tag for that, too. Or in the case of
looking for more removal options on the
Doom Blade page, we can see there's a
couple of tags that might interest us.
Removal, removal creature, and removal
creature destroy.
Let's click the removal tag for now.
This will take us to a page with every
card in the game that's classified as
removal. As the description at the top
of the page mentions, spot or limited
removal. Now, once I found a certain tag
I want to look through, I click this
button here. This will take me back to
the main Scriall search engine, and it
will even give me a keyword for
searching tags. Here it is, O tag. You
can also use the keyword function for
the same result.
From here, I can add other keywords that
we've learned to narrow down this
search. Let's add color identity,
commander format. We want it to be an
instant, and for it to be able to target
non-land permanence.
Now, this gives us a nice list of cards
to browse through.
Here's another tip. With this search
term we've entered, there's an excellent
piece of removal that I noticed that's
not here. Generous gift. Now, the reason
it's not there is because we've told
Scrile to explicitly look for the oracle
text that says non-land and generous
gift can hit any permanent. So, here's
how we can fix that. If we're wanting to
find something with one condition or
another, we can use parentheses and the
or keyword. It's pretty
self-explanatory.
Let's change our search condition to
search for both nonland and permanent in
the oracle text. And now with this, we
get cards like Chaos Warp and Generous
Gift added to our results. Now, there
are some cards that have slipped into
this search that perhaps you weren't
expecting to see. And to deal with
those, we need to cover regular
expressions, which is a topic that needs
its own video. Now, that's everything
you need to know to kick off your
searching on Scriall. If you have any
questions, let me know in the comments
down below. Be sure to like this video
if you learned something and if you want
to learn about regular expressions next.
Thanks again to boot.dev for sponsoring
this video and thanks to you for
watching. I'll see you in the next one.